25 chapter 26 Of Black Beauty LibriVox recording is in the public domain Black Beauty by Anna
suul chapter 26 How it Ended It must have been nearly midnight
when I heard at a great distance the sound of a horse's
feet. Sometimes the sound died away, then it grew clearer again and
nearer. The road to 's Hall l through woods that belonged to the earl; the
sound came in that direction, and I hoped it might be someone coming inside search of
us. As the sound came nearer and nearer I was almost sure I could distinguish
Ginger's step; a little nearer still, and I could tell she was in the dog cut I
ned loudly, and was overjoyed to hear an answering Nay from Ginger, and men's
voices. They came slowly over the stones, and stopped at the dark figure that lay upon the
ground. One of the men jumped out, and stooped down over it. “It is Reuben,” he
said, “and he does not stir!” The other man followed, and bent
over him. “He's dead,” he said; “feel how cold his hands
are.” They raised him up, but there was no life, and his hair was soaked with
blood. They laid him down again, and came and looked at me. They soon saw my cut
knees. “Why, the horse has been down and thrown him! Who would have thought the
black horse would have done that? Nobody thought he could fall. Reuben must must
have been lying here for hours! Odd, too, that the horse has not moved from the
place.” Robert then attempted to lead me forward. I made a step, but almost fell
again hello he's bad in his foot as well as his knees. Look here— —his hoof is cut
all to pieces; he might well come down, poor fellow! I tell you what, Ned, I'm
afraid it hasn't been all right with Reuben. Just think of his riding a horse
over these stones without a shoe! Why, if he had been in his right senses he would
just as soon tried to ride him over the moon. I'm afraid it has been the old
thing over again. Poor Susan! she looked awfully pale when she came to my house
to ask if he had not come home. She may believe she was not a bit anxious, and
talked of a lot of things that might have kept him. But for all that she
begged me to go and meet him. But what must we do? There's the horse to get home
as well as the body, and that will be no easy matter.” Then followed a conversation
between them, till it was agreed that Robert, as the groom, should lead me, and
that Ned must take the body. It was a hard job to get it into
the dog cart for there was no one to hold Ginger; but she knew as well as I
did what was going on, and stood as still as a
stone. I noticed that, because, if she had a fault, it was that she was impatient in
standing. Ned started off very slowly with his sad load, and Robert came and
looked at my foot again; then he took his handkerchief and bound it close ly round,
and so he led me home. I shall never forget that night walk; it was more than 3
miles. Robert led me on very slowly, and I limped and hobbled on as well as I could
with great pain I'm sure he was sorry for me, for he often patted and encouraged me, talking
to me in a pleasant voice. At last I reached my own box, and
had some corn; and after Robert had wrapped up my knees in wet cloths, he
tied up my foot in a brown pus to draw out the heat and cleanse it before the
horse doctor saw it in the morning, and I managed to get myself down on the straw,
and slept in spite of the pain. The next day after the farer had
examined my wounds, he said he hoped the joint was not injured; and if so, I should
not be spoiled for work, but I should never lose the
blemish. I believe they did the best to make a good cure, but it was a long and
painful one. Proud flesh, as they called it, came up in my knees, and was burned
out with Corti and when at last it was healed, they put a blistering fluid over
the front of both knees to bring all the hair off; they had some reason for this,
and I suppose it was all right. As Smith's death had been so
sudden, and no one was there to see it, there was an inquest held. The landlord
and Hustler at the White Lion, with several other people, gave evidence that
he was intoxicated when he started from the inn. The keeper of the Tollgate said
he roded a hard gallop through the gate; and my shoe was picked up among the
stones, so that the case was quite plain to them, and I was cleared of all
blame. Everybody pied Susan. She was nearly out of her mind; she kept saying
over and over again, “Oh! he was so good— —so good! It was all that cursed drink; why
will they sell that cursed drink? Oh Reuben, Reuben!” So she went on till after he was
buried; and then, as she had no home or relations, she, with her six little
children, was obliged once more to leave the pleasant home by the tall oak trees
and go into that great gloomy Union House end of chapter